Rushil Singh



rushilsingh@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/rushilsingh



https://rushilsingh.dev

Summary

With over six years of experience, I am a proficient software engineer specializing in data engineering pipelines, full-stack application development, and cross-platform app development. My work ethic, adherence to best practices, and commitment to lifelong learning have consistently resulted in the successful delivery of top-notch projects.

Experience



🐧 Software Engineer

Synamedia

Feb 2020 - Present (3 years 5 months)

- · Spearheaded the development of innovative anti-piracy and addressable advertising solutions as a Software Engineer at Synamedia.
- Specialized in designing and implementing data engineering pipelines in AWS, leveraging various technologies for efficient processing.
- Utilized Python for writing backend code, developing AWS Lambda functions, and building ETL jobs for data processing in AWS.
- Expertise in building robust full-stack applications utilizing the MERN stack (MongoDB, Express, React, and Node.js).
- Successfully consolidated disparate code bases into a single, unified solution by employing Flutter for cross-platform application development, significantly reducing redundant efforts and streamlining the development process.

Volen Software Engineer

Volen Software Services Pvt. Ltd.,

Sep 2019 - Feb 2020 (6 months)

- Played a pivotal role in developing an anti-piracy solution for Synamedia, a leading provider of video infrastructure solutions, while working as a Software Engineer at Volen Software Services
- Focused on Python-based frameworks to develop high-quality, client-oriented software solutions
- Offered a full-time role at Synamedia due to outstanding performance and ability to deliver top-tier solutions, further advancing career in the software engineering field

Software Engineer

ACL Digital

May 2017 - Jun 2019 (2 years 2 months)

- Managed orchestration of network devices, appliances, and virtual appliances in the SDN and NFV space
- Developed Resource Adapters to communicate with devices on the south- bound interface using device-specific protocols and converted retrieved data to JSON for use by other north-bound REST applications



Teaching Assistant

The University of British Columbia

Jan 2013 - Apr 2013 (4 months)

- Acquired experience in course administration, curriculum development, and student mentorship as a Teaching Assistant for the Cognitive Systems course (COGS 300) at The University of British Columbia
- Acted as a bridge between students and the professor, facilitating feedback, problem-solving, and efficient course management
- Crafted laboratory tasks, supervised lab sessions, maintained and moderated the course website, and assessed lab reports and exams

Education



The University of British Columbia

Bachelor of Science (BSc), Cognitive Systems

Cognitive Systems is an multidisciplinary program, a combination of the fields of Computer Science, Philosophy, Psychology, Neuroscience, and Linguistics. There are different streams which emphasize certain fields more heavily. I was in the Computational Intelligence and Design stream which emphasises Computer Science more so than the other adjacent domains.



The Doon School

Indian School Certificate (ISC), Physics, Chemistry, Mathematics, Computer Science, English

Skills

Python • JavaScript • Flutter • Dart • MERN Stack • React.js • MongoDB • PySpark • Amazon Web Services (AWS) • Azure Databricks

Honors & Awards



President's Entrance Scholarship - UBC

Sep 2009